Mikaeel Khalid

Full Stack Developer

<u>LinkedIn</u>

mikaeelkhalid@icloud.com

Mobile

+92 321 3340009

Full Stack Developer being proficient in front and backend coding, including designing user interactions on websites, developing servers and databases for website functionality and coding for mobile platforms. Proven experience as a full stack developer or similar role the skill sets includes:

- Multiple front-end languages and libraries (e.g. HTML5/ CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript, HTML DOM, JSON, jQuery).
- Multiple back-end languages (e.g. PHP, Java, Python, C++, SQL, Node.js).
- Familiarity with databases (e.g. MySQL, MongoDB), web servers (e.g. Apache) and UI/UX design.
- Proficiently understand Object-Oriented Programming, Data Structures, and Algorithm analysis & design.
- Hands-on tools include XAMPP, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Spark Post for iPad Pro, XCode, VirtualBox, PhpStorm, Visual Studio Code, Brackets.
- Excellent communication and teamwork skills.

Education

FAST – National University of Computer & Emerging Sciences

2021

BS Honor Computer Science

Certifications

Machine Learning 2019

Stanford University (Coursera.org)

Experience

Full Stack Developer

National University of Computer and Emerging Sciences

Aug 2019 – Feb 2020

Being solo Full Stack Developer responsible for developing and designing front end web architecture, ensuring the responsiveness of applications and working alongside graphic designers for web design features, among others include:

- Develop a project from scratch adding features like admin panel, enhance GUI as delivering a final project to replace with an existing website.
- Designed, developed and kept adding new function and UI to the Fast National University of Computer and Emerging Sciences Peshawar Campus web portal.
- Developed the website using Core PHP, Bootstrap v3.3.6, JavaScript, jQuery, Ajax, and MySQL.

- Architect, Design, Developed and configured an optimal database for all data needs.
- Developed Admin Panel where Admin can have full control to post Latest News,
 Upcoming Events, QEC Events, Notices to Noticeboard, Alumni Feedback, Pop up Latest
 News and Admissions.
- Used Bootstrap to designed the Front End of the website.
- Used Core PHP (Procedural) for backend services (Admin Panel), MySQL DB for database services and Ajax for forms validations.
- MailChimp subscribers form Integration for newsletters.
- Cross-browser Compatibility with Edge, IE9+, Firefox, Safari, Opera, and Chrome.
- Fully Responsive on all devices & Google Maps via data attributes.
- Responsible to manage cPanel activities.

International Conference on Emerging Technologies (IEEE).

Oct 2019 - Dec 2019

- Head of Web & IT (Student Body).
- My duties including in this tenure is to develop a website for International Conference on Emerging Technologies 2019 (ICET '19), hosted by Fast - NUCES Peshawar.
- Developed the website using Core PHP, Bootstrap, JavaScript, and jQuery.
- Integration of data from various back-end services and databases.

Web Developer

Prosigns Technologies

July 2013 - Oct 2014

- Implementation of UI designs and coding, creating reusable objects and templates, wireframes for web pages and email templates; manage maintenance, updates, expansions, and scaling of each design.
- Building reusable code and libraries for future use.
- Integration of the front-end and back-end aspects of the web application.
- Implementation of a robust set of services and APIs to power the web application.
- Designing Wordpress Website, Plugins & Theme Customizations.

Campus Activities

Lead Web Strategist

NUCES ACM Student Chapter

Aug 2019 - Present

Key Deliverables:

Lead Web Strategist of NUCES ACM Student Chapter Society.

IT Teacher

Hope Society (Project 50 Kids).

Aug 2019 - Present

Key Deliverables:

- As a Group IT Teacher, we visited targeted orphanage schools to teach them what is code? How to code in Scratch Programming Language, how to use google and basics of current technologies, etc.
- We do one activity of two days in every semester, in one targeted orphanage school.

Organizer

TECH KP 2020

Key Deliverables:

• Photographer & Organizer of the event, the event was organized to make awareness of technology in the province, which was attended by KP ministers and special guest Tania Aidrus (Head of Digital Pakistan).

Academic Projects in each Semesters

Food Ordering System (Android App) -- OOAD

Developed a Food Ordering System in Android Studio. Implemented in Java and Firebase as a BaaS database.

• Followed AGILE Methodology for the development process.

Attendance System -- Database Systems

Developed an Attendance System to help teachers in taking attendance by only showing attendance code to students.

Implemented in core PHP, JavaScript, Bootstrap and MySQL.

Quiz Maker -- COAL

Developed a Quiz Maker using assembly language (masm32) with mouse handling and interrupts.

Digital Clock -- Digital Logic Design

Created a Digital Clock using logic gates.

Library Management System -- Computer Programming

Developed a Library Management System using C++ (OOP).